Guide to the Collected reproductions of Hu Shih papers at Cornell University, 1910-1963.
Collected reproductions of Hu Shih papers at Cornell University, 1910-1963
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collected reproductions of Hu Shih papers at Cornell University, 1910-1963.
41-5-2578
Shih Hu, 1891-1962.
Microfilm of correspondence, photographs, manuscripts, news clippings, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
This collection of materials was created to bring together and preserve the documentation that now exists on Hu Shih (Cornell University Class of 1914), in the Department of Manuscripts and University Archives of the Cornell University Library.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
This collection of materials was created to bring together and preserve the documentation that now exists on Hu Shih (Cornell University Class of 1914), in the Department of Manuscripts and University Archives of the Cornell University Library. Beginning with the original Hu Shih Collection (#41-5-219), we added his correspondence with Woodford Patterson (6-2-2168) and other friends from his Cornell years, and parts of the Deane W. Malott Papers (3-6-65), the Lincoln Patterson Scrapbooks (#37-6-334), the Cosmopolitan Club Records (#37-4-145), the Alumni Office Records (#41-2-877), and several other items collected individually over the years.
Newspaper clippings were photocopied before filming and articles judged easily accessible, such as those in Asia, were not filmed.
The appendices of The Bulletin of the Institute of History and Philology, Academia Sinica, vol. XXXIV, pt. 2; Taipei, Taiwan, Republic of China, 1963, "In Memory of the Late Dr. Hu Shih (1891-1962)" are bibliographies of Hu Shih's writings in Chinese and western languages and of his poetry and unpublished manuscripts in Chinese. They should be consulted for a complete listing of his work.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hu, Shih, 1891-1962.; Malott, Deane W. (Deane Waldo), 1898-; Patterson, Lincoln E.; Patterson, Woodford, 1870-1948.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University. Office of Alumni Affairs.; Cosmopolitan Club (Cornell University).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
This microfilm has been digitized and is available online here http://hdl.handle.net/1813/36425.
Additional material can be found online at the Hu Shih and Cornell University Library Website, http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/hushih
RELATED MATERIALS
See also List of books presented to Cornell University Library by Chinese students, #13-1-501.
Facsimile reproductions of Hu Shih's diaries; from September 1912 to February 1918, are available in the volume 胡适留学日记手稿本 / Hu Shi liu xue ri ji shou gao ben, call number Asia Rare CT3990.H78 A3 2015 +++
CONTAINER LIST
- Biographical material including photographs of Hu Shih and and his wife, Tung-Sher Kiang (June 1913), 28 pieces. (Reel 1)
- Correspondence including a letter from his mother to Mrs. Patterson, 20 pieces. (Reel 1)
- Manuscript poems by Hu Shih, in English, 3 pieces. (Reel 1)
- "Ezra Cornell" by Hu Shih, four editions in Chinese, 7 pieces. (Reel 1)
- Other writings by Hu Shih (Reel 1)
  - "A Republic for China", Jan. 1912 (Reel 1)
  - "The Ideal Missionary", Feb. 1913 (Reel 1)
  - ""Cornell Welcomes the Delegates to the Ninth Conference of the Eastern Section", June 10, 1913 (Reel 1)
  - "Marriage Customs in China", June 1914 (Reel 1)
  - "The Philosophy of Browning and Confucianism", Jan. 19, 1915 (Reel 1)
  - Forward to The Tenth Anniversary Cornell Cosmopolitan Club Calendar, 1915 (Reel 1)
  - "Analysis of the Monarchical Restoration in China", Jan. 14, 1916 (Reel 1)
  - "Is There a Substitute for Force in International Relations?", June 1916 (Reel 1)
  - "Intellectual Preparedness", June 10, 1940 (Reel 1)
  - "The Place of the Alumni Organization in the History of Universities", Nov. 15, 1940 (Reel 1)
  - Speech before the Economic Club of New York, Mar. 16, 1942 (Reel 1)
  - Broadcast of Friends in the United Nations, Mar. 22, 1942 (Reel 1)
- Writings about Hu Shih (Reel 1)
  - "The New Literary Movement in China" (mss. copy), Jan. 1917 (Reel 1)
  - Brief sketch for Cornell Alumni News, Dec. 26, 1919 (Reel 1)
  - "A Scholar Pleads for China", June 11, 1939 (Reel 1)
  - Copy of Citation, June 17, 1939 (Reel 1)
  - "The Influence of the Canoe on the Chinese Literary Revolution", May 22, 1941 (Reel 1)
  - "Dr. Hu Shih to be Sixty-third Commencement Speaker", June 1941 (Reel 1)
  - "Ambassador Hu Shih", Dec. 15, 1941 (Reel 1)
  - "At the Chinese Embassy", Aug. 1942 (Reel 1)
  - "China's Gentleman and Scholar", Dec. 1942 (Reel 1)
  - Messenger Lectures Program, Mar. 1, 1946 (Reel 1)
  - "Young Sage", Dec. 22, 1947 (Reel 1)
  - "Bright Feather", Jan. 19, 1953 (Reel 1)
  - "A Tribute to Dr. Hu Shih", Mar.-Apr. 1962 (Reel 1)
  - "Hu Shih, Incurable Optimist", ca. 1962 (Reel 1)
  - "Biography of Dr. Hu Shih", n.d. (Reel 1)
- Newspaper Clippings, 87 pieces. (Reel 1)
- The Hu Shih Memorial Scholarship Fund, 13 pieces. (Reel 1)
- Miscellany, 8 pieces. (Reel 1)